Good morning.
As everyone...
Thanks...
out to the last the build conference really appreciate you guys being here who also the of
...last night...cool awesome hope you guys
have had a great time and I've seen a lot of powerpoint confess I've
got a few more slides for you but I've got a lot of cool demos going to spend a lot of time
in visual studio look at a lot of code for the slides I do have
you can rest assured that powerpoint was harmed in the making of this presentation.
I'm david...program manager on the media team here at microsoft...
only my privilege to be here today talking to you all about what we've done some make it easy
and awesome to build audio and video applications for
windows.
...tell you review the session afterwards we really appreciate the
feedback it helps us make sure that we can give you better and better presentations
image build conference so you could take a few moments will appreciate
it before we get into the content of the talk I wanted to take a moment and step back and
reflect on what the goals that we had is immediate team were for windows
developers with windows time first and foremost we wanted to give you.
What you asked for we heard a lot of feedback from you that things were hard that
it could be easier if we could do a better job making use successful
...platforms we heard that feedback
wasn't always easy we heard a loud and clear we've listened to it and we've delivered on
it we've given you the top things that you ask for with windows
...second you've heard about...a lot but it's critical is
a shared goal with everyone here at microsoft to make it possible
for-you to write one piece of code the runs across all windows
our devices give you that reach and that scale that billion devices that
...talked about the other day we believe is critical for making
...successful we want you to get the maximum return on your investments when you target
the windows platform and we've really taken that on
is our mission within media deliver on that?
Finally we want to allow you to focus on what makes your app
great.
Media is a somewhat unique space and there's a lot of value
provided in a lot of different parts of the stack by a lot of different companies some companies
are really selling the content that they provide to users other companies are selling the services
and application development and even specific areas of that so we wanted to make
it really easy...the language of your choice bid csharp javascript
cplus-plus whatever you prefer to focus on that unique value...
your providing to the ecosystem what windows handle all the other stuff all that stuff that's
hard that you don't really want to be writing code for
...taking on that work...making it easy for you to focus on your key value.
So, we'll talk about today we'll spend the first half so talking about building
converge audio apps and how you can write that one audio app that runs on all
devices?
And, they will build on what we learned with the audio and talk about how you can add
advanced video experiences...app...super easy we've taken things that used
to required thousands lines of code and dropped down into a
handful alliance some really excited thinking to level we have in-store.
...want before we get into it as want to be really clear I get a lot of questions on
...everything I show today runs on every single
device running windows ten with the universal windows platform everything I
show will run on devices from pc phone tablet xbox hollow
...whatever we come up with next you write this one
set of code it's going to run their...your customers are going to love it.
When you think about building an audio application the first thing you really want to think about
is how you user is going to use that application?
Most people probably almost every day with us and
music or other audio files on your pc what you do you go you load up
your favorite app you set what you want to listen to be a some
cd content that you've...to your library files
...downloaded or streaming you set up whatever you want to listen to and then you go
do something else you don't stay in that app you're going to be writing code...to be surfing
the web maybe you're cooking dinner doesn't matter what you're doing all that matters is that
you're not running the audio application anymore so when you think about building
an audio app is important to think about this user interaction model and really
designed for background audio...talk about background audio really talking about that
experience with the users minimize their app and they're doing something else but they want to keep...
your music and loving the experience you provide in the past.
We had different stories for backhoe audio on different devices the code you had to write
on your pc was different from the code that you had to write for
phone.
Wanted to make this easy converge it so we've taken the approach that
we pioneered on windows phone we brought that to the full range of devices how
this approach works it's actually a to process based approach I'll get into the reasons for that
moment but the first processes
you'll see is this rich player app that's all
the ui and everything that you users going to interact with and figure out what they want to listen to and
tell you what to play the second processes a low memory background task.
This task communicates with your player app.
So, that you can tell it what audio file should be
played and then it's responsible for actually playing those files the reason that we take this
to process approach is because windows runs on this huge range of devices
you've heard about for really high-end desktops and high-end phones and stuff
there's a lot of resources available but on a low-end phone, you know, if you think about the seventy
five-dollar phone that someone's buying because they broke their phone...I want to shell out six hundred bucks
or their an emerging market is low...devices don't have a lot of resources available
and you want to be really careful about how those resources are utilized so by splitting out the ui
code from the actual media playing code it allows us the operating system
to go tear down this ui when the user goes only
star browsing the web we can tear down all that ui free up those resources for other
things and that's great for use a developer because by enabling
the operating system to be really efficient with these resources we get a lot of our savings so
that we can keep your app running as long as possible we think this provides a lot of value for both the
users of your applications and use a developer in terms of keeping your app in front
of the user do all the communication in the playback through a background media player
...this is an object the operating system provides to-you
...facilitates two main things.
...allows you to communicate between your background task and a rich player app so
that you can keep these two items and sinking working together well and...it also provides you with
the media player that you use to actually play the audio content.
use this player and this gives you kind of a core experience that you want for the app but there's one more
piece of the puzzle and that's the system media transport controls.
I like to think of these is the operating system level ui that
the user sees so after they've gone in the browsing the web they might
hit a song that they listen to recently and they want to skip over...with something new if
they're on a keyboard if there are a desktop they might hit the next key media key
hundred keyboard and by interacting with the system media transport controls
...background task and receive those events and it can know that
...skip to the next track the user just change the volume so you get all of that
operating system level interaction that the user is going to expect to be available for them
when they go and actually run your application and use it in conjunction with
other apps so you want as you start to write a
background audio app take a few minutes look through the...we have
...msdn it does a really great job showing you how all this works together and just kind of make
sure you understand the architecture that you want to build...take
...few minutes up-front and getting that architecture in
mine's it set you up for success so you can build...really great application down the line.
It's really easy to semis messages with the background media player
so in this case we just got a really basic scenario where.
The users in your application ui and they've quick the next track button
...want to listen to something else.
Using the background media player with the send message to background method you can just send a
string in this case I've chosen max but any arbitrary string that you want to send you can
send from that foreground process to background process will receive that string
...no hey when I get the keyword maxed
...and extract the...world listen to this anymore.
So, it's really simple to get these basic messages but we also know for a lot of
you want to build something more complex were string passing isn't sufficient so we also support
sending values sets and this example...what you'll see if you go download our msdn
sample since we think this is really the way a lot of you want
to designer applications in the msdn sample you'll see that there's three.
Projects and the via solution the first project is that rich player app
ui mentioned.
The second project is that low memory background
...the third is a share has some shared classes between the two that
are used for communication so in this case we define a message service class
they can send a bunch of classes that we've defiance you've got...skip next message
classes skip previous message class and a bunch of other ones...powerful
with these classes you can define was data contracts and then you can use that to
send rich information between the two.
So, in this case when you send a message to the background will...value set the first item in the
value set is the name of the class that we're sending and then the second item we add
...value set is we serialized that...
...a stylistic choice you could say that serialized xml or any other format your choice but you
...class and then you take that value set and you send that to
your background task.
Background task is an able to go and parcel this and get rich information perhaps you
wanted to send how long the user was loosing that track so that you can take some action on matter build
some analytics you do all that here so with that let's jump...quick demo and see what I'm talking about.
So, I wrote that the first and foremost what I have here...just kind of
...audio and you'll notice...I minimize that.
Audio cuts out real simple...kind of demonstrates why background audio...
In this case what I have here is I've got the windows eight one music app which is implement
a background audio you'll notice now when I play.
Music I can minimize the...an audio.
What you...might notice that...with...
tracks however is that there's...positive between each...
And, the reason those audible positive exist because of windows
eight one we did not have support for gap with audio this
...been a top customer pinpoint...we've heard in the
...developers and users...excited to announce that with windows ten
we've added support for the platform a background audio.
And, what I love about the approach that we've...we really solved to developer
...points with one solution we've added support for a set
of playlist api is...make it really easy for you to manage these playlist
that works for both audio and video files and when you use these playlist api
is you get gap with audio support for free out-of-the-box
with no additional code required for you we do this in two ways?
First and foremost we look at the files that you're playing windows mp threes
are encoded it's possible for the encoder to write a set of meta data to those
tracks the details exactly where audio silence
exists.
Not stepping back moment...key source of those gaps in the playlist is that when audio
encoded the encoder can write a little bit of extra white space between it so if you're ripping a
cd that's a common source of
that so the encoder can detail where that spaces been added and
then we playback those tracks will parse that metadata and will snip out
those little pieces of space so that you get that campus experience?
At the same time we recognize that a lot of users they don't know what encoder they
used when they rip their cd library they don't care they just want all of it to
work and they don't understand why do these files play back gap...of these...gaps.
So, to support those files that do not have that metadata present we've also added
a set...to the platform so
we're playing back any other audio file we
...heuristics to sniff out whereas some white space been introduced and
...slice set out again so that no matter what file you're playing always gap was audio.
So, I've got a code sly boats go ahead and just jump into visual studio.
what I've got here is this is just the this is a modified version of the msdn sample
we've got online for-you and the code that you
see is the code for actually creating one of these play lists?
The first thing you do is you go and create a new playback list object in this case
we've enabled looping on that as well we have a list of songs
...just iterate through those songs.
And, for each your song
...that we encounter will create a new media source.
We set a couple custom properties in this case and this the track...title key
this is totally optional but we think will be really nice for use developers because
...provides...for you download...to go query and see what's
...that's playing you could go look up the track id entitle key to see what the users
listening to when they hit that skip next button so once you set up your source using
...turn that into a media playback item and add that to your playback list.
We go through we add all of our items the playback list.
And, then you simply set that is your source on your
background media player and you'll see that now when you have five.
Sample come up and now when we listen to it
we'll get a gap was experiences seamlessly switches between.
you can even minimize that and everything...why'd you...the list they have no idea what
...for which the contract...retract for doesn't matter
so, we think that you're going to love this is a developer because it makes your life easier writing these apps
and users ago love the fact that you've got gap...audio support.
There's one last.
Thing to keep in mind when we talk about audio and that's that
we talked about music a lot right now but there's a lot more audio that gets played
through the platform for movies and music to communications
and games there's a ton of different audio
those different categories of audio have different expectations in terms of how the audio
is process and used, for example, if you're single movie what the user to be able to hear the
quiet whispers to the loud explosions and to do so in a
way that doesn't I'm constantly fiddling with the volume control in order to get
a good experience communication app on the other hand you really want to make sure that the
...the vocals come through clearing...understandable so there's different filters that
you want to provide for these audio.
Categories so we defined a set of categories
...the platform it's really easy for use a developer to set you just set it on
your media element and never worry about it again and then windows
...take this information and we use...communicate with the audio driver to make sure
that we provide the best possible experience when you users or...to audio.
So, we think all this is really great it'll make it really easy
...to write one audio app that runs on all those devices when you think about these audio categories its
important remember him when we talk about video as well.
Video you generally going to set the movie category and playback.
When you think about video today however one of the big things that you
hear a lot is the term adaptive streaming adaptive streaming is how you can
target that huge range of devices that will run?
From the sm phone on a three-g network to your xbox with
the four-k tv in a really fast internet connection it's a way to
have a set of video files that provide the best experience for each
user each device running on any network real quick for those
you who aren't familiar with the term adapt...kind of this the term...refers to a collection
of technologies that can be used to provide that create experience on devices
...a high-level how it works is you've got your video file that you actually want to play back
all these devices you can then take that file and you can encoded in a bunch of different
bit rates so you can go from really low-quality to really high-quality with different bandwidth
requirements for supporting each of those and then you can chop all those video files up into a bunch
of segments is a to for maybe ten second chunks of video.
And, then you have a manifest file is on the server you have a manifest file
the describes here's all the video content that's available here's how I can access this
content is you can download it and playback for the user there's a
lot of solutions out there for how you can create this content, for example,
as your media services has a great set they've got a talk on...two to three so if you want to
learn more about the service side of this encourage you to go to that talk regardless of
if you use as your another service provider you get all your content up in the cloud.
And, then on the client-side you have a streaming client...clients responsible for
downloading that manifest determining what contents available play and play
back the best content for that user...device...going to
...initial video segment to download it's going to download that and start...back to the user and while
it does so it's going to be monitoring network conditions it's going to figure out is
this the best file for this user on this device if files
are downloading really fast and there's a lot of extra bandwidth will go switch to higher-quality video so
the user gets better viewing experience the other hand if the
...downloading slowly and there's not enough network throughput
...support playing back that file without buffering it...switch down to a
lower quality bit rate so that you can ensure that you avoid those painful buffers
and providing great seamless viewing experience for the user so as its playback this
...constantly
downloading new segments and switching between them to provide the best possible experience.
Some of the common technologies that we see...use...today
...which is a specification that's developed by apple and they actually require
...for streaming to ios devices over cellular networks.
...dash which is an iso standard that seeing really brought adoption especially
in...the world such as europe and dashes it's
...standard so people really like to reference and build on this solution
that's interoperable and available to everyone the third one is smooth streaming which is the technology
that microsoft developed and four years ago for solving
the same problem with smooth streaming we actually took all
...that technology we published all the specifications release...ip
related to it and it was one of the key inputs into the dashing this reform as
they defined initial standard so we like think of dashes smooth streaming plus
input from a lot of other companies and technologies and kind of the conglomeration of the best
ideas that we've seen in the industry and, it's a really great solution that people are starting to roll-out today.
Overall as a company
however we know that there's a lot of content that exist today that's we
want-to make sure please great on windows and there's a lot of content that's coming from the future
...really committed to interoperable media so in the past...only had the smooth streaming
sdk available for windows and phone eight one applications we've also
got ahead we've added support in the platform for both the...in-dash protocols.
Now you can see...this is awesome let's go.
When I say we've got platform support I mean that it's as easy as with
one-line of code you can get fully adaptive streaming h alas in-dash
content and that's available for both applications and websites you
can set the source of either of video tag or
...media element to a to...dash manifest and
will handle everything from there will download the manifest will parse it will play
it back is really powerful we've also gone ahead and
...updating the smooth streaming sdk for windows ten so for all of you who
can use that to build eight one apps
this sdk will be available it's going to be online very soon?
And,...make it really easy for you to go ahead and take your existing
...one app and move it to windows
...as and not have to rewrite...your video streaming code.
So, this is really powerful for...sites but we also recognize that a lot of
people want support for customization...to...some of
the a experience without having to go rewrite or go
right an entire streaming client so common use case that I've heard from developers
that they want to control the initial bit rate that's downloaded and playback this
...powerful because there's a lot of different user experience...a can
duluth be delivered with that initial bit rate.
For example,
if the initial bit rates the lowest quality stream available you're going to
get really, really fast time to first frame it's going to be like that and you're going to be
...content for the user and then you can ramp up to high-quality stream from there.
Other people prefer starting it really high-quality and they don't want to see that ramp up so they'd
rather take a little extra time up-front and...that really high-quality furs frames that
...video looks great from the moment you start so we've got
...for this so that you can control what the initial bit rate is along with a bunch
of other customizations we'll get a few we get into the code there's a lot more
...msdn we think that we provided a great set of default
values and provide a great default experience but we want to be a dictator for
how streaming behaves on the platform so we want to provide you with that customization
so that and we know that some of you want even more customization
in windows aone we added support for
...it's a set of wthree-c api is.
...it really easy in the browser to...adaptive streaming application
...you to parse...and start downloading
those video segments and play them back without having to actually...video segments you can just few
minutes of buffer developers have been really happy with this technology and we've seen a lot uptick we
wanted to make that easy for use animal developers out there as well so we've gone ahead
and we've created a winner...projection of the microsoft see api surface
so that you can use that from any language of your choice.
Makes a really easy removes a lot of boiler plate code that you had to write for building a streaming
app so for those of you who desire that for custom solution
that should be great for you works with media protection manager for
dr am in xhtml csharp case and not only do
...we added support for mp for which we had in the browser...one we've also
...support for mpeg...transport streams which is the container used fridge
...so you can go ahead and use this technology for building both custom
dash nhl us players as well as...so let's
get some code and see just how easy it really is to add this to...application.
Let's see that is another one.
...cool so what I
have here is I've just got a blank csharp project that I created.
Demo in csharp today because it's language and I'm most comfortable...but if you prefer
...cplus-plus another language works the same for you there.
So, create the...projects you don't have to watch me get that open and we'll just go
ahead and start by putting in some really basic ui...the application.
We go ahead and build...you'll see as we just got a grid with three rows
the first row has just a text box...a button where you can set whatever
manifest you want to play the application we're going to build today by the way supports
playback of both hl...and dash content
their zero api differences between the two streaming technologies so makes a really
...if...considering a move,
for example, from a...us the dash is a great way to support your existing library
and your new content is a comes online so
...the text box takes in a manifest the play button...transport controls and just the
con thecopyright attribution at the bottom but obviously when I quick play nothing
happens we need to actually go and wire up support for adaptive streaming.
So, how you can do that is first off we need to add support we need to add?
Quick method handler so you can add the event and then using
...twelve it's really easy to just pop over into cs file...support.
what we do is with the first-line...code we go ahead and we grab the
...that's from that text box we convert it
to system uri and then we'll set that as the source on the
media element and that's it go ahead and run that project
...start streaming back in this case I believe I have an ageless
...them there when you could play quite...your
...by my robot hand moi?
So, this is awesome and,
you know, two minutes you've got ahead you built-in application that's capable of playing both
...and dash content...fully adaptive makes a really easy
for you but I know you sitting there and say well that's great but,
you know, I've seen a lot in the news about close captions and I've heard from
lawyers that I have to support close captions if
I'm in america and it's also just really important that I support on my users.
In the past for close captions we've seen a lot of people views the player framework
sdk that's open-source online for adding those closed caption experiences
steer app it's hard it's not code than anybody wants to write so
we've gone ahead with windows...and added native support for
close captions to the platform supports all the top formats
and delivery mechanisms today...have six to eight or six and seven
...captions in your si header you can use to html you can use web
...bunch of other caption formats whichever one
...using we support that we've got a place
...the os where the user can customize it this is really powerful think about
...you can in the case of using...in-band close captions,
for example,...lines of code you meet all of your fcc requirements and
...have a great experience if you want to add support for
adam band there's a few lines of code that you need to
...so the first thing you need to do you need to initialize
...media source adapted media source is
the underlying source that was created when we set that manifest on the media element
so by default will go ahead and wire that up and creative for you but if you want use close captions
...some of those customization api as I mentioned you need to add some you need to add this and
here app so the first thing we'll do is.
We'll go ahead...add that and now rather than setting the...we call this method that we've created.
...just pass in the
manifestly want to play the url to it as well as the media element that we want
in here what we do is we create an adaptive media source creation objects that.
Object tells us were successful in creating at
...provide a bunch error information if we were able to create either due to
...uri or network conditions are many other errors.
then once it's created we can go ahead and grab that media source I'm going to quickly.
...the top of the class and just going to find this object to.
Make a really easy for us to work with all...through this project.
So, we've got our adaptive media source object and now we need to go ahead and add closed caption support
...building real application you're probably going to have your closed caption file
posted online somewhere that you downloading but for the sake of this demo I'm just going
to grab html file that I added earlier today.
So, you can take a look this is just standard html.
We're going-to go ahead and tag this is contents so
the visual studiopick setup properly for the build process.
And, then we're going to do is we're going-to go ahead.
Tags html file...closed caption track.
An added term media source.
So, the first thing we do is we go and we create a media source objects former
...media source.
Next we're going to get grab the url to that
...file and we'll use...create a...source.
And, with that timedtext source we can then add it to are media source so now we've
...the adaptive streaming media source
with the tty html source...we can play those back and sank.
Once you've got your source created you can then create a media playback item
and set that item on your media player and now we run the application
will see not only do we have a fully adaptive app but it supports close captions as well.
We go ahead...good...freaked out by my robot and you'll notice moi.
We've got a closed caption button that's now been automatically added
to the media controls windows is picked up the close captions
our presence in the file we put that button there and you can turn it on
...with our moi.
As we although it's not just sufficient
have captions they need to be user customizable and to do that you can go ahead and go
into the settings application and ease of access you'll notice we've
added closed caption tab if you go there there's a ton of different
customizations user can set they can specify their font the background et cetera
so perhaps we'll say for this example I really like my captions and read I think the makes
of lot easier for me to read as I can go ahead and set that up what I
could play
this is really, really powerful and it's great for users as well because they can just go
set up their preferences one-time and then it works across all of their video
applications you don't have to write any code users get the experience they
expect...this is a huge win for the platform.
If you do want to write your own render I will mention that all of the q objects that
we were setting there they're all available to so you can go pick up all those caption
...and do whatever you want them?
So, this is really powerful but we know that with player framework there's another key
scenario was used for allows for customizing the controls.
With in the past the media controls were not easy to customize so you couldn't make
them fit in with the look and feel of your application we've got ahead and we've added supports
the platform for customizable media controls as well so it's really,
really easy for you to take your app and make it look great with the ui that
you've built so, for example, let's say we want to add a little color
...I know my boss she absolutely loves orange is
your favorite color she's always telling me that oranges
the new black so I want to add a little origin there for her.
What you can do?
You can just add a resource dictionary to your app dot example
file is to keep brushes that you want to update the first is a system control highlight accent
And, the other is the system control foreground...brush.
...these both the orange and now when I run the application you'll see that we've added a splash
orange to the app so it starts to look better I know my boss is going to love having that
support...freaked out by my robot hand moi so
it super easy and we think the this will go a long way towards making the
ui fit in better with your app at the same time however we know that a lot of you want to do even more
advance things.
You want to update you want to add new buttons you want to
disable buttons you want to change the dropout order
when I say dropout order what I mean is that on a ten foot...
...xbox experience you could fit a lot more buttons on the
timeline when you're on a three inch phone so we've got
away free to do all of this and more.
And, how that works you can just go ahead and grab the generic
dot sample file from your sdk?
So, everything that we showed there is all the
...that's available for you to go ahead and use the build a custom set
of controls for application it's really easy to do so all you have to do and
...is good...I've got the sdk here it's been long paths will be
...msdn it'll be easy if you to find don't worry about writing this down.
You can just grab...generic
downsample file what you'll see is that this is this has all of the code
...for...throughout the applications go ahead and open this...visual studio you want to make
sure you do and open with...like visual studio so you can
get access to the code so now you can just go ahead and search for the media
transport controls and you'll find them down here online twelve thousand three hundred eighty one.
Go ahead minimize that and just copy and paste the whole thing.
You take it back to the application that you're building.
Is...quick things to do to wired up the first thing I'm going to do is
...to add a new folder to store this file will caught themes?
Within the seems...add any resource dictionary.
We'll call it a generic does animal.
Generic
...samples nice makes it easy for purpose of the demo because it just automatically gets picked up when
your application runs.
Go ahead and update this...name space.
And, we just want to
paced all that code we grabbed you'll see it's a lot it's twelve,
twelve hundred lines of code and that's because we're doing a lot of things on your behalf they you don't want
to do there's only a few hundred line hundred so lines of coding here that you actually care about so you can get
rid of all the resources all the visual states stuff all that management that you don't care
about accessibility support these things are important for building a great application but
that don't really give you any value you can minimize that ignore it never worry about it again
then you can come down and you'll find.
Thecommand bar section command bar is where all the controls that we've seen on
the ui actually exist their listed in left to right order
there's a couple key properties to note here the first one is the dropout or
dropout order specifies as your application scales from large
the smaller from small the large which buttons take precedence for appearing
on the ui so in this case the stop button we have that by default set to
dropout order
of one which means that if you can't fit every single button on the screen it's going to be the first button
...fall off that's because...play in...the user can use
to generally get the same...fact we don't see what a usage of that.
In fact because we don't see much usage is also set to collapse by default
...turn it on throughs...here or we've also got api
for turning on buttons as well so you can look through and you'll see that we've got a lot of great buttons for-you
by default summer on by default summer off but available for use.
And, there's a couple keep buttons one of them is the closed caption
button we talked about earlier this is said to collapse by default
...handle turning that on and off for you because captions or such
an important part of the user experience we automatically turn that button on
...their present so...users always in control and you don't have to worry about when captions
are present or not the other button that will do the same thing for you is with the audio
track selection button...multiple audio tracks in the file you're playing whether it's either and
mp for the...locally or if you're streaming content over the web light up that
selection button whenever it's appropriate so that the user can switch between say english and spanish.
So, we've got a great set of buttons for you but.
As we mentioned earlier there's a lot of strong opinions around how streaming
should behave and if you want high-quality or to start low-quality and stuff I personally
I really like seeing my videos and high-quality all the time and I want to add a high
...button the application the one collects just locks
onto the highest quality bit rate and streams at that I'm willing to risk some buffering
...a lower quality experience in that sense that I get that real...
video experience so this is really easy with our new controls to go ahead and add that button.
We just create a quick buttoned I've...the dropout
order to eleven because this is really important in my opinion for the quality experience for the app that
we're building today have gone ahead and I've made that visible.
You can see that I've just gone ahead and we'll just show up is hq.
On the playback timeline.
So, once you've gone ahead and
you've added this you want to make sure by the way that you update.
Your target type here's what's reference
...by your app so-called...custom media transport controls.
And, they...go back to our main page does...ad these controls the media.
So, we references transport controls you'll see
...also turning on a couple buttons of turned on the playback rate button and the zoom
enabled button think those are important the user experience and I really like
the playback rate button because sometimes I have to watch training videos...I want to be able to turn that on
to a faster speeding get the quicker.
What...added...is one more piece?
We need to do and that's we need to go ahead and add a new class
...are custom controls the cs file.
Within this class will go ahead and wire up or buttons.
So, we create a new instance...the media transport controls
will go ahead and reference...name space.
Just supply.
Template so now when you have five we'll see that
...are high-quality button to the application.
...is awesome but, you know, doesn't do anything there's no way
we have an added support for actually locking onto that bit rate let's go ahead and do that now?
The first thing that we need to do is we're going to go...a new event.
That handles when that high-quality buttons clicked.
And,...were also going to have a button that
tracks visual...because we want to highlight that button when it's on into...when it's awesome.
So, now what you'll see is when.
That buttons clicked.
Assuming you first we check to make sure...applications actually registered for that
about if it has we go ahead...fire the event and then we update the ui so
we're just updating the foreground property on that hq text
...that we had...setting it's orange so fits and look or fuel looking
...our app when it's enabled all tagger back to white when it's disabled.
Next we'll go back to our application will handle that event.
...that buttons clicked we're also going to quickly.
At a reference to variable that we use for tracking the state.
Within this as well.
We'll have this disabled by default so we get adaptive streaming.
Now when the buttons...
We're going to use a couple new properties if you look at the adaptive media source you'll see
we've got a ton of different properties download bit rate playback bit rate a lot
of events for-you it's all msdn I encourage you to check it out there and play around with it
in this case is to two things that we need we need to be able to set the minimum bit
rate so we can sept this so that are streaming our will never go below that bit rate
and...want to set that to the highest quality bit rate that's available so we can use
...available bit rates property the gives us the list sordid from low
to high of all the bit rates available by setting the minimum bit rate that we stream
width to the highest quality bit rate available
...effectively locking on to that high-quality bit rate.
We'll go ahead and track that...enabled the buttons clicked again we can go ahead and set that to
You can...amac spit rate it's not a surface that...you said it's a null and that'll
...so that you can switch back to streaming adaptive.
The last thing we need to do is we need to actually register for the events of this codes called what's correct.
So, we simply handle out event and now when I...five.
Will be able to actually play the application lock onto a...bit rate?
Why don't you...that your freaked out by my
...can see moi?
...really fast internet...so it's not necessary easy to see that
were locking on we've got that rates show you the download and play back so I encourage you to
...take this code later improve it out and you'll see that we
switch to that bit rate so once that buttons collect all future segment downloads will be at the highest
quality bit rate and you can go ahead and turn that button off as well.
So, this is all super powerful but kind of
...getting a lot of controls on our main playback timeline it's getting crowded and
sone highlight some of my some of the best controls to keep the...clean and simple for the user
...do that you can go back to the generic does animal file we created with our custom controls.
And, then down here you'll notice we've added within our command bar these are all
primary commands you can also add a set of secondary commands.
And, these are all commands...show up and overflow menu that when this is created
we'll see in a second...in our case I think the playback rate button
in the zoom buttons that we turned on...a really important to the overall experience and
its important functionality but it's kind of an each audience so we want put that...
overflow menu so it's available just for the people who want to see that you can go ahead and you can do it all this code all
you need for the overflow menu is settle label called this one playback rate.
And, then for resume will go ahead and call that zero.
So, now we move the buttons here you'll see will run the application they no longer show up on that
main timeline and now we've got this...
...when you click this you can see we've got the playback...playback...for example, gives you a bunch of...
default options but again you can customize all of this to meet your needs.
So, this provides a really nice clean experiencing keep the
controls fitting in with the look and feel that you one of your application.
We're really excited about this functionality we think you're going to lovett the last fifteen twenty
minutes we've been able to build an application that fully supports hl
...and dash streaming we've got custom controls that we've
...to look great in
our application including custom buttons for functionality that's important to
our application and we've done it all with full support for user customizable
close captions this is awesome this is going to relieve a ton of
...so we've heard from you guys and really make you happy.
So, I'll skip over these slides I've got
them for the people online if you want to go back and recap what I talked about but,
the key message we want you to becoming...here with you should move
...platform but do so...your own pace we know
lot-a you out there have a lot of existing investments and using a lot of technologies to deliver windows
...one applications and all those are still fully supported on windows
ten we think that the platform provides a lot of really great value to you and you're going to
want to move to the platform and take advantage of it so you want to plan that but planet within your
existing business-cycle your development cycles it's really easy to get to windows ten
there's no high-cost you don't have to go rewrite code you don't have to move from smooth
streaming...dash you can keep using the hl...the k all of this stuff just works and you can
move the pace that makes sense for you to that and sdk
...as the player framework sdk they're going to be updated in the coming months to
take advantage of all these features so it'll turn into a thinner and thinner wrapper on top...platform...
So,...we talk about first and foremost we listen
...feedback and we want more of it
...be painful at times but that feedback is critical to us is how we
know what's the most important features for us to build to make you all successful
...committed to making your lives easy
...it really easy...to build awesome apps and make a lot of money on windows so give us
...feedback I've got an email address at the...the resource
section slide I encourage you reach out tell us what you like play with the api is
if you like something let us know if you don't like something we really want to know that you don't
like it if something news hard there's a new challenge you want to solve.
That feedback is awesome it's how we make sure that we build the features that you need.
We added support based on your feedback for gap with audio
...dash custom controls closed caption all part of the platform
now this was hard in the past we made it really easy for you and you're
...love it.
It's we think that the changes we've made
it's easy to build powerful media application on windows
...cutting-edge technology available for you to use to
delight your users without having to take along a lot of pain and code on your side.
as you walk out here today...building an audio app to...background audio
and mind think about that up-front so you can set yourself up for success.
And, focus your development on what makes your app great where you provide
key value to the ecosystem focus all your engineering efforts there
and for all that other stuff that boiler plate that cost of doing business what windows
do that for you and start using our features today everything that I talked about
in the bits that you've downloaded you can start using the features today
and it's awesome...one small caveat I'll point out which is our gap...support is coming in
a future flight the playlist api
...available so the your own blocks to start developing against all of this and you'll get
a few quick updates down the line to make that's even better.
So, with references media feedback microsoft-dot-com sentence
email let us know what you think.
We've got a blog post ways to sent out a few months ago talks about...to us in-dash
in the browser we've got api references so,
check it out start using it tell us what you think thank you so much for your time if you
send...we really appreciate it.